Before we go back to our motion model and how we can simplify
在回顾运动模型、如何简化
the relations between the states and to give them values,
状态之间的关系并给状态赋值之前
I want to introduce the first order Markov Assumption.
我想介绍一阶马尔可夫假设
Assume you want to estimate the posterior distribution
假设你想估算给定之前状态时
of p x_t given our previous states,
Pxt 的后验分布
and you have no observations or controls.
并且你没有观察或控制
So this is a pretty simple example but it works fine to explain the Markov Assumption.
这是个很简单的例子 但可以很好地解释马尔可夫假设
You can write this distribution as
分布可以写作
the following: This relation can be represented as a chain.
如下： 这个关系可以表示为一个链
For example, to estimate or predict x_1,
例如 要估算或预测 X1
we only use x_0.
我们只需要 X0
To estimate x_2, we use x_1 and x_0.
要估算 X2 我们使用 X1 和 X0
And finally, for x_3,
最后 对于 X3
we use x_2, x_1, and x_0.
我们使用 X2、X1 和 X0
In this example, the Markov Assumption postulates that x_2 is the best predictor for x_3.
在本例中 马尔可夫假设假定 X2 是 X3 的最佳预测条件
This means, that the other states, x_1 and x_0,
这意味着其他状态 X1 和 X0
arts or future states, carry
或者未来的状态
no additional information to predict x_3 in a better way far more accurately.
均不包括能更好或更准确地预测 X3 的额外信息
We also say the state x_2 is complete.
我们也可以说 状态 X2 是完备的
We remove the links or connectors between x_1 and x_3,
我们删除从 X1 到 X3 之间的连线
and x_0 and x_3,
以及 X0 到 X 3 之间的连线
which means x_3 is independent of x_0 and x_1,
这表示 X3 独立于 X0 和 X1
it only depends on x_2.
它只依赖于 X2
And of course, for x_2, it is the same.
当然 对于 X2 也是一样的
This means, you can also remove this guy over here.
也即是说 你也可以删除这条连线
Since we now assume,
因为我们现在假设
that x_t only depends on the previous state,
Xt 只依赖于前一个状态
we can rewrite the posterior in this way.
这个后验可以重写如下
So, if we want to continue this chain,
因此 如果我们要继续这个状态链
which means to predict the future,
也就是说 如果要预测未来
we only take x_3 into consideration.
我们只需考虑 X3
An example could be a weather forecaster,
天气预报就是一个例子
the weather of tomorrow only depends on today and
明天的天气只依赖于今天
today includes our previous information and is uncertain, of course.
今天包括了之前的所有信息 当然是不确定的
As an important fact,
很重要的一点是
we have to assume that we have an initial guess for x_0.
我们必须假设 我们对 X0 有一个初始猜测
So, x_0 must be initialized correctly.
因此 X0 必须正确初始化
Let's go back to our motion model and I will show
我们回到运动模型
you how we can benefit from the Markov Assumption.
我来展示如何利用马尔可夫假设
Before I talked about the Markov assumption,
之前我们学到马尔可夫假设时
I stopped here and ask you,
我在这里听了下来 问了一个问题：
how we can simplify the structure?
如何简化这个结构？
Now, I will show you how the Markov Assumption can help us here.
现在 我会告诉你在这里如何使用马尔可夫假设
First, I split the control vector into the current control,
首先 我把控制向量分割为当前控制
u_t, and our previous controls.
ut 和之前控制。
Now, let's take a look to the first term,
现在 我们看看第一项
the probability distribution of p x_t is conditioned by x_t minus one,
Pxt 的概率分布受条件 Xt-1
all previous observations or controls, and the map.
所有之前的观察或控制、以及地图的限制
Here, we apply the Markov Assumption the first time,
这里 我们首次应用马尔可夫假设
since you already know x_t minus one,
因为你已经知道 Xt-1
set one_to_t minus one,
Z1:t-1
and u 1_to_t minus one will not carry
和 U1:t-1 不包括任何
additional information to predict x_t in a better way.
能更好地预测 Xt 的额外信息
These values were already used to estimate x_t minus one.
这些值已经用来估算 Xt-1 了
This means, x_t is independent of these values.
这表示 Xt 独立于这些值
Because of this fact,
因此
we can remove these two conditions in the graph.
我们可以在图中删除这两个条件
This will result in the following,
然后得到了这个
and the posterior distribution of x_t only depends on x_t minus one,
此外 Xt 的后验分布只依赖于 Xt-1
u_t, and the map.
Ut 和地图
This term is called,
这一项叫做
the transition or system model,
转换或系统模型
which predicts or which moves the previous state in the new one.
它可以预测新状态 或移动新状态中的就状态
And as you can see,
你可以看到
we do not need the whole observation or control history.
我们不需要整个观察或控制历史
Here, you can also consider that the map,
这里 你可以认为地图
m, does not influence x_t.
m 不影响 Xt
It is common practice to neglect m,
忽略 m 是常见操作
but here, we keep it.
但这里我们保留 m
The second term describes a posterior distribution of x_t minus one,
第二项描述了 Xt-1 的后验分布
given all previous observations or controls, and the map.
条件是所有之前的观察或控制、以及地图
Here, we use a Markov Assumption again.
这里 我们再次使用马尔可夫假设
We assume that u_t tells us nothing about x_t minus one,
我们假设 ut 不包括 Xt-1 的任何信息
because u_t is in the future.
因为 ut 在未来的时间
We ignore u_t to estimate the state,
我们在预测状态 Xt-1
x_t minus one, and we move this condition over here.
时忽略了 ut 并移动这个条件
Based on this assumption,
根据这个假设
we rewrite the motion model again.
我们重写运动模型
After these two steps,
这两个步骤后
we achieved a really, really important step.
我们来到了一个非常、非常重要的步骤
I ask you, do you know why?
知道为什么吗？